PERSEVERENCE SAVIERI

+32 494 33 89 78 · perseverencesavieri@gmail.com · LinkedIn Avenue Clays 60, Schaarbeek, 1030 Brussels

SUMMARY

I am a PhD candidate in medical sciences in the Biostatistics and Medical Informatics research group (BISI) at Vrije Universiteit within the Department of Public Health. My research focuses on developing R Shiny applications to enhance statistical thinking among non-statisticians. In parallel with my research, I am a principal statistical consultant for the university core facility, Support for Quantitative and Qualitative Research (SQUARE). I offer broadscale statistical and methodological quantitative support through consultations, statistical coaching, data analyses and workshops.

STRENGTHS AND EXPERTISE

- Data Analysis & Visualisation
 Research & Collaboration
- Project Management
- Strategic Planning
- Consulting
- Leadership & Coaching
- Communication & Presentation
- Statistical Software (R, STATA, SAS & SPSS)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Vrije Universiteit Brussels, Brussels, Belgium

Oct 2021 - Present

- **Principal Statistical Consultant**
- Provide statistical and methodological support for research grant applications.
- Offer consultations, statistical coaching, data analyses, and lead workshops.
- Collaborate with researchers to design robust studies and develop comprehensive data analysis plans.

Teach Me 2, Cape Town, South Africa

Apr 2021 - Oct 2021

- **Academic Coach**
 - Delivered one-on-one math and statistics tutoring, leading to a 60% improvement in client grades.
 - Utilised specialised techniques and accommodations to enhance academic success.

African Cancer Institute, Cape Town, South Africa

Jun 2020 - Sep 2020

- **Biostatistics Intern**
- · Conducted primary and secondary analyses of cancer datasets using R and STATA.
- Assisted in study design, sample size calculation, and statistical analysis plan development.
- · Supported research proposals with statistical reports and manuscript writing and presented findings internally.

Stellenbosch University, Cape Town, South Africa Teaching Assistant

Feb 2020 - Jun 2020

 Guided and supported first-year MSc Biostatistics students in data management and statistical programming using R and STATA.

EDUCATION

Vrije Universiteit Brussels, Brussels, Belgium

PhD in Medical Sciences (Biostatistics) | Sep 2021 - Present

Stellenbosch University, Cape Town, South Africa

MSc in Biostatistics | Feb 2019 - Mar 2021

University of Zimbabwe, Harare, Zimbabwe

Bachelor's in Mathematics & Statistics | Aug 2010 - Jun 2014

References are available on request.